PAUL CATHEY

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

ABOUT

I'm engaged by the building and understanding of beautiful systems from code to philosophy to teaching.

I've been in Web Development for the past 2 years working on consumer-facing fin-tech applications currently with a mostly remote team.

I have mainly written and maintained Rails code bases backed with MySQL and Mongo DBs. I've been communicating with merchants across the country to deliver changes for thousand-store product launches.

I also have been maintaining an AWS infrastructure with DevOps tools such as Teraform and Ansible.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer (Delivery Team)

Smartpay Leasing | Sep. 2018 - Present

- Developing on front and backend projects in RoR apps
- Working with vendors on integration to ship code to thousands of stores
- Guiding DevOps/security improvements for PCI audit
- Composing documentation (Confluence) for internal systems and practices
- Helping drive team culture during company transition

Production Support DevOps Engineer

Smartpay Leasing | April 2017 - Sep. 2018

- Resolved real-time and ongoing issues from customers and internal
- Supported dev team with bug fixes, code reviews and knowledge transfer
- Organized team events and gave a talk on solid Slack-etiquette and skills
- Ran recruitment drive and interviewed candidates for team
- Jedi Award recipient for work with Boost Mobile payment system migration

EDUCATION

App Academy

September-December 2016 | San Francisco, CA

- Web development 1000-hour bootcamp with a 3% acceptance rate
- Stacks included RoR, React, JS ES6, SQL, jQuery, git, HTML, CSS3
- Received 100% grade from all daily pair programming peers

St. Olaf College

2009 - 2013 | Northfield, Minnesota

- BA Philosophy & Asian Studies Relevant coursework:
- Formal Logic
- Computer Science Intro (Python)

CONTACT

pmcathey@gmail.com (408) 641 - 6101 Oakland, CA github.com/mooserson
in linkedin.com/in/pmcathey/
paulcathey.com